Michael Gerasymenko



Customer and quality focused mobile engineer in love with mobile platforms. I am bringing on board over 14 years of software development experience, 12 years of iOS experience. My aim is to bring the team and the product to the next level. I have experience working on great products and I am excited to see them used.

т	C •
Language	proficiency
Lair Gaage	promotoricy

English Full professional proficiency

German Verhandlungssicher

Ukrainian, Mother tongue

Russian

Education

2007–2013 Master of Applied Mathematics,

National I. I. Mechnikov University

Odessa, Ukraine

2003–2007 High School, Richelieu Lyceum

Qualifications

- $_{\odot}$ Hands-on coding experience with Swift, Objective-C, JavaScript, TypeScript
- o Knowledge in setting up and maintaining the CI processes and pipelines
- o Conference and internal presentations: public speaking experience on 500+ events
- o Building the teams: hand-on experience in interviewing and hiring
- o Knowledge in classical algorithms, graph theory, database design, network

Conferences

 Speaker at UIKonf 2018 (End-to-end encryption for iOS developer).
Attendee at WWDC 2016 and 2022 conference

Product Awards

- o Wire: 2015 German Design Award
- o STILL EASY: 2013, 2014 Red Dot Design Award, 2013 Deutscher Preis für Wirtschaftskommunikation, 2013 iF communication design award, 2013 Annual Multimedia Award Gold

Experience

2022 Staff iOS Engineer, Delivery Hero SE, Berlin

Mobile engineering infrastructure team: building the right tools for the big team to work efficiently. Design system implementation, automated tests, CI pipeline improvements, deployment, monitoring, architecture.

2021 Staff Dev Lead, Onfido LTD, Remote, from Berlin

Leading engineering team at Onfido

Aug 2020 — Chief Technology Officer, Feeld Ltd, Remote, from Berlin

Sep 2021 Fully remote role. Overtook the team faced with multiple challenges. Built and managed the high performance engineering team in the growth phase, defining the team structure, leading the leaders, defining the company IT strategy. Customer-centric, product-driven approach. Doubled the team size, created the data team setup for the company by hiring the leading data engineers and data scientists.

Oct 2019 — Chief Technology Officer, Cara Care, Berlin, Germany

Aug 2020 Strategic planning, data security and privacy design, relations, architecture design, regular 1-1 conversations.

2019 **Team Lead**, Sharecare, Berlin, Germany

Team leadership, regular 1-1 conversations, mobile app development, technical leadership.

2014 — 2019 **Team Lead**, Wire, Berlin, Germany

2012 — 2014 Technical Lead, InnoMoS GmbH, Bielefeld, Germany

2010 — 2013 Software Engineer (iOS), SoftTechnics LLC, Odessa, Ukraine

2008 — 2010 Software Engineer (iOS), Readdle Inc, Odessa, Ukraine

2007 — 2008 Software Engineer, Wildix Srl, Odessa, Ukraine, E-Commerce